Guide to the Robert Kraushaar papers, [ca. 1970-1990]
Kraushaar, Robert papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert Kraushaar papers, [ca. 1970-1990]
6754
Robert. Kraushaar
6 cubic ft.
Printed Materials, Publications, Reports, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records relating to planning in Great Britain, including the Greater London Council, Sheffield, other British cities, and Community Development Projects.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
City planner.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records relating to planning in Great Britain, including the Greater London Council, Sheffield, other British cities, and Community Development Projects.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kraushaar, Robert.
Subjects:
City planning--Great Britain.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Forms part of Progressive Cities and Neighborhood Planning Collections.
CONTAINER LIST
- Greater London Council Popular Planning Unit. The People's Plan for the Royal Docks, London: Newham Docklands Forum, 1983., 1983; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder loose)
  Original Publication: 39 pages
- Eisenschitz, Aram and North, David. "The London Industrial Strategy: Socialist Transformation or Modernising Capitalism?" [no publisher, date given], Article (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photocopy: 21 pages
- Wainwright, Hilary. "The Limits of Labourism: 1987 and Beyond," from The New Left Review, #164, July/August 1987, pp. 34-50, July/August 1987; Article (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photocopy: 17pages
- Travers, Tony. "London after Abolition," Local Government Studies, Croydon: Charles Knight Publishing, May/June 1990, pp. 105-116, May/June 1990; Article (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photocopy: 2 copies, 12 pages each
- Heseltine, Michael. Where There's A Will, London: Hutchinson [no date given]., Document (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photocopy. Two chapters: 2, 14
- "Propaganda by Examples: The Economic Policies of the Greater London Council," Critical Social Policy, pp. 64-71 [no publisher, date given], Article (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Photocopy: 8 pages
- The Public Sector as Industrial Property Developer: Learning from the GLC's Experience in Developing Industrial Property, London: Calvert's Press [no date given]., Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Original Publication: 23 pages
- Greater London Enterprise Board. Greater London Enterprise Board Limitied Annual Report and Accounts (31st March 1985), London: Greater London Enterprise Board, 1985., March 31, 1985 March 31, 1985; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Original Publication: 41 pages
- Greater London Council. Community Areas Policy: Record of Achievement, London: Greater London Council, Transportation and Development Department, 1985., 1985; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Original Publication: 60 pages
- Greater London Training Board. Annual Report 1984, London: Greater London Council, 1985., 1985; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Original Publication: 34 pages
- Islington Council. Working for Jobs: Developing an Employment Strategy and Programme. London: Isington Council, 1987., 1987; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Original Publication: 28 pages
- Industry and Employment Branch of the Department of Recreation and Arts. The State of the Art or the Art of the State?: Strategies for the Cultural Industries in London. London: Greater London Council, 1985., 1985; Book (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Original Publicaiton: 176 pages
- Greater London Council. Working for London the Final Five Years: A Summary of the GLC's Achievements, 1980-1985, London: Greater London Council, 1986., 1986; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Original Publication: 80 pages
- Committee of Inquiry into the Conduct of Local Authority Business. "Chapter 10: Recommendations," Report of the Committee, London: Committee of Inquiry into the Conduct of Local Authority Business, 1986., May 9, 1986 May 9, 1986; Document (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Photocopy: 14 pages
- Prosperity of Slump?: The Future of Wendsworth Economy, Document (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Photocopy: 29 pages
- Greater Long Regional Council of the Labour Party. Report of the Industry and Employment Working Party, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Photocopy: 70 pages
- House of Commons. House of Commons Official Report: Parliamentary Debates (Hansard), Vol. 996, No. 19, 1980., December 19, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Photocopy: 11 pages of Transcript
- House of Commons. House of Commons Official Report: Parliamentary Debates (Hansard), Vol. 5, No. 111, 1981., June 5, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Photocopy: 6 pages of Transcript
- House of Commons. House of Commons Official Report: Parliamentary Debates (Hansard), Vol. 973, No. 68, Part II, 1979., November 16, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Photocopy: 4 pages of Transcript
- Department of the Environment Welsh Office. Rates: Proposals for Rate Limitation and Reform of the Rating System, Londong: Her Majesty's Stationery Office, 1983., August 1983; Document (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Photocopy: 23 pages
- Department of the Environment Welsh Office. Streamlining the Cities: Government Proposals for Reorganising Local Government in Greater London and the Metropolitan Counties, London: Her Majesty's Stationery Office, 1983., October 1983; Document (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Photocopy: 25 pages
- Capital Issues: The Journal of the London Strategic Policy Unit, London: London Strategic Policy Unit, No. 1, Nov. 1986, November 1983; Journal (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Original Publication: 19 pages
- Greater London Enterprise Board. Turning the Tables: Towards a Strategy for the London Furniture Industry, London: Greater London Enterprise Board [no date given], Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Original Publication: 2 copies, 26 pages each
- The London Energy & Employment Network. London Energy Action Plan, London: London Energy and Employment Network, 1986., 1986; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Original Publication: 45 pages
- Greater London Enterprise Board. Altered Images: Towards a Strategy for London's Cultural Industries, London: Greater London Enterprise Board [no date given], Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Original Publications: 2 copies, 26 pages each
- Greater London Enterprise Board. Printing Matters: Towards a Strategy for the London Printing Industry. London: Greater London Enterprise Board [ no date given]., Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Original Publication: 20 pages
- Ward, Michale. "Labours's Capital Gains: The GLC Experience," Marxism Today, December 1983, pp. 24-29., December 1983; Article (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Photocopy: 6 pages
- Newman, Ines. "Greater London Enterprise Board: Vising and Reality," Local Economy, No. 2, Summer 1986., Summer 1986; Article (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Photocopy: 13 pages
- "Canary Warbling." The Economist, July 27, 1991. pp. 77, 80., July 27, 1991; Article (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Original Copy: 2 pages
- Linton, Martin. "Capital Service." New Socialist, No. 68, August/September 1990. pp. 6-11., August/September, 1990; Article (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Rustin, Michael. "Lessons of the London Industrial Stragegy." [no other information given], Article (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Photocopy: 12 pages
- Policy Review Sub-Committee of the London Burough of Wandsworth. "Prosperity or Slump? The Future of Wandsworth's Economy." London: The Policy Reivew Sub-Committee of the London Burough of Wandsworth, 1976., October 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Photocopy: 48 pages
- Grow, Daniel F.. "Introduction: Socialism, Relative Autonomy, and the Local State," introduction to Relative Autonomy and Local Socialims: The Greater London Council's Local Economic Strategy, 1981-86. Dissertation. [no date given], Document (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Original Copy: 38 pages
- Greater London Enterprise Board. Corporate Plan 1985-1986. London: Greater London Enterprise Board, 1985, 1985; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Orignial Publication: 54 pages
- Greater London Council. Planning for the Future of London: Draft Road Network Alterations to the Greater London Development Plan, London: Greater London Council, 1984., 1984; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Original Publication: 23 pages. Includes maps and diagrams.
- Greater London Council. Planning for the Future of London: Race and Planning Guidelines, London: Greater London Council [no date given], Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Original Publication: 31 pages
- Greater London Council. Planning for the Future of London: Alterations to the Greater London Dvelopment Plan. London: Greater London Council, July 1984., July 1984; Book (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Orignial Publication: 87 pages. Includes maps and diagrams.
- Greater London Council. Planning for the Future of London: The Greater London Development Plan. London: Greater London Council, Sept. 1984., September 1984; Book (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Original Publication: 238 pages. Includes maps and diagrams
- Greater London Council. "Technology Networks. Item 7, IEC 413." London: Industry and Employment Committee of Greater London Council, 1982., July 22, 1982; Document (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Photocopy: 5 pages
- Greater London Council. "Overseas Promotion and Marketing Review: Additional Information. Item 5, IEC 178." London: Industry and Employment Committee of the Greater London Council, 1982), February 8, 1982; Document (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Photocopy: 2 pages; attached to "Overseas Promotion and Marketing Activities: A Review"
- Greater London Council. "Overseas Promotion and Marketing Activities: A Review. Item 20(1), IEC 146." London: Industry and Employment Committee of the Greater London Council, 1981., December 7, 1981; Document (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Photocopy: 10 pages; attached to "Overseas Promotion and Marketing Review: Additional Information"
- Greater London Council. "Interim Appraisal Criteria. Item 5, IEC 410." Industry and Employment Committee, Finance and General Purposes Committee of General London Council, 1982), December 22, 1982; Document (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Greater London Council. "Greater London Enterprise Board." London: Industry and Employment Committee of the Greater London Council, 1982., June 3, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Greater London Council. "Technology Networks. Item 7, IEC 413." London: Industry and Employment Committee of Greater London Council, 1982., July 22, 1982; Document (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Joint Docklands Action Group. "Job Descriptions of Resource Centre Team." London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1976., October 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Photocopy: 3 pages; job description
- Joint Docklands Action Group Resource Center. Docklands - The Fight for the Future. London: Joint Docklands Actinal Group Resource Center, 1977., September 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Photocopy: 36 pages
- Joint Docklands Action Group. Docklands: The Fight for A Future. Joint Docklands Action Group, 1976., March 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 12)
- "Interview with Marjorie Mayo of the Joint Docklands Action Group--September 15, 1977." [no other information given], September 15, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Photocopy: 6 pages; question and answer format
- Joing Docklands Action Group. Tower Hamlets: The Fight for a Future. London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1975., December 1975; Document (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Docklands Joint Committee. London Docklands Operational Programme, 1978-1982. London: Docklands Joint Committee, July 1978., July 1978; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Original Publication: 86 pages; bound document
- Joing Docklands Action Group. Rebuilding Docklands: Cuts and athe Need for Public Investment. London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1977., September 1977; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Original Publication: 40 pages
- Joint Docklands Action Group & Tower Hamlets Action Committee on Jobs. London's Docks: An Alternative Strategy. London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1978., July 1978; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Original Publication: 9 pages
- Tower Hamlets Committee on Jobs. A Training Strategy for Tower Hamlets. Written by the Tower Hamlets Committee on Jobs for the Tower Hamlets Training Forum. London: Tower Hamlets Committee on Jobs, 1977., 1977; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Joing Docklands Action Group. The Engineering Industry in Docklands. London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1978., April 1978; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Original Publication: 35 pages
- Joint Docklands Action Group Resource Center. Docklands: Two Years On. Written by the Joint Docklands Action Group Resource Center for the Docklands Forum Conference. London: Joint Docklands Action Group Resource Center, 1978., April 1978; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Orginal Publication: 29 pages
- Joint Docklands Action Group Resource Team. "Inner City Policy: Partnership and Docklands." London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1977., November 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photocopy: 2 pages
- East End Docklands Action Group. "Why EEDAG are Opposed to the Consultants' Proposals for a Wapping East-West Road." London: East End Docklands Action Group. [no date given], Document (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photocopy: 3 pages
- The Docklands Forum. "The Future of the Docklands: Statement of the Docklands Forum." [no information given], Document (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Young People and Work." [no information given], Document (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Joint Docklands Action Group. "Joint Docklands Action Group." London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1977., November 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Docklands Joint Committee. "JDAG Finances. Docks 136." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., August 28, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photocopy: 7 pages
- Vigars, Leonard. "Docks Plan may be too Late." Evening News. July 9, 1976., July 9, 1976.; Article (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photocopy: 1 page, missing
- Joint Docklands Action Group. "Joint Docklands Action Group Resource Center - Grant Application." London: Joint Docklands Action Group, 1977., November 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 15)
- London Strategic Policy Unit. Information Pack. London: London Strategic Policy Unit (no date given)., Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Orignal Publication printed for new employees
- Audit Commisioner of England. "Impact on Local Authority's Block Grants." London: The Audit Commision for Local Authorities in England and Wales, [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Photocopy: 9 pages
- London Docklands Development Corporation. "Isle of Dogs, Wapping, Limehouse, & Poplar Street Plan, Fourth Ed. - June 1990." London: London Docklands Development Corporation, 1990., June 1990; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Original Publication
- Docklands Light Railway. "Docklands: The Growing Railway." London: Docklands Light Railway, Ltd., 1990., Summer 1990; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Wallis, H.F.. "The Dockland Desert: an Inner City Tragedy." Municipal Review, No. 576, Dec. 1977., December 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Photocopy: 4 pages
- Owen, Kenneth. "Electronic Revolution 'May Lead to the Dole.'" London Times. May 4, 1978, p. 1-2., May 4, 1978; Newspaper Clipping (Box 1, Folder 18)
- "Area Development in Europe: Strong Need to Confront Troubled Rural and Urban Regions." International Herald Tribune. Paris: New York Times and Washington Post, 1978., April 1978; Newspaper (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Original Publication: 8 pages
- Docklands Joint Committee. A Policy for Public Involvement in Docklands Development. London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1974., August 1974; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Orignial Publication: 11 pages
- Docklands Joint Committee. A Strategy for Docklands: Setting the Scene. London: Joint Docklands Committee, 1975., January 1975; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Original Publication: 36 pages
- Docklands Joint Committee. Work and Industry in East London. London: Joint Docklands Committee, 1975., April 1975; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Original Publication: 43 pages
- Docklands Joint Committee. Shopping. London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1975., June 1975; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Original Publication: 24 pages
- Docklands Joint Committee. The Docklands Spine--Tube, Bus, or Tram? London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1975., April 1975; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Docklands Joint Committee. Education, Helath, Welfare, and Recreation. London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1975., July 1975; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Greater London Council Public Information Branch. "Transport Plan for Docklands." Pulic Information Branch News Service. No. 308. London: Greater London Council, 1977., July 14, 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Original Copy: 3 pages
- Greater London Council Public Information Branch. "Docklands: Dramatic Change for the Better." Pulic Information Branch News Service. No. 192. London: Greater London Council, 1977., June 3, 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Original Copy: 1 page
- Greater London Council Public Information Branch. "New £27 Million Road to Open up Docklands." Pulic Information Branch News Service. No. 456. London: Greater London Council, 1977., November 3, 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Greater London Council Public Information Branch. "GLC will go it Alone on Docklands Peter Shore told to 'Stop Dithering.'" Public Information Branch News Service. No. 309. London: Greater London Council, 1977., July 14, 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Original Copy: 1 page.
- Greater London Council Public Information Branch. "£27M Transport 'Jugular Vein' for Docklands." Public Information Branch News Service. No. 447. London: Greater London Council, 1977., November 1, 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Greater London Council Public Information Branch. "Jubilee Line: Preparatory Drilling Begins." Public Information Branch News Service. No. 217. London: Greater London Council, 1977., June 30, 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 20)
- The Economist. London: The Economist Newspaper, Ltd., 1977. January 1-7, 1977., January 1-7, 1977; Magazine (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Original Publication: 90 pages
- Candler, David. "Summary of Press Comment on London Docklands - A Strategic Plan: A Draft for Public Consultation." London: Docklands Development Team, 1976., July 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Haywood, Steve. "Flower of the East?" Time Out. October 7-13, 1977, No. 392., October 7-13, 1977; Article (Box 1, Folder 21)
- [no author provided] "Employment in Lewisham." London Burough of Lewisham. [no date provided]., [no date provided]; Document (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Original Copy: 166 pages
- Docklands Development Team. "Draft Docklands Strategy--The Public Response. Further Comments Receive. Docks 132A." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., July 12, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Development Team. "'Setting the Scene' (Docks 36) and 'Work and Industry in East London (Docks 55) - Results of Public Consultation. Docks 75." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1975., August 27, 1975; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Photocopy: 19 pages
- Docklands Development Team. "Public Consultation on the Draft Strategy. Docks 84." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1975., August 19, 1975; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Development Team. "Docklands Redevelopment - Statement by the Secretary of State for the Environment. Docks 137." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., August 23, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Photocopy: 9 pages. Includes the transcript of the Secretary of State's announcement and the Docklands Joint Committee's response to that announcement.
- Docklands Development Team. "Government's Inner City Proposals: (i) White paper, (ii) Construction Works. Docks 201A" London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., June 17, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Development Team. "Delegation of Greater London Council's Planning Powers to The Docklands Joint Committee. Docks 138" London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., August 23, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Joint Committee. "Statement on the Machinery Established for Promoting Industrial Development in Docklands." London: Docklands Joint Committee [no date given]., Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Joint Committee Finance Officer. "Economic and Business Activity in Docklands - The Role of the Local Authorities and Finance. Docks 179." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., February 25, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Development Team. "Docklands Housing Density. Docks 197." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., June 9, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Joint Committee. "Report (18.1.77) of the Development Applications Sub-Committee. Docks 163." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., January 18, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Docklands Development Team. "Draft Docklands Strategy - Comments by DJC Constituent Authorities. Docks 131." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., July 8, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Photocopy: 27 pages
- Docklands Development Team. "Northern Relief Route - Interim Progress Report. Docks 202." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., June 13, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Photocopy: 2 pages. Includes the pamphlet for the Proposed Docklands Northern Relief Route
- Greater London Council. "The Road Limehouse to Canning Town: The Proposed Docklands Northern Relief Route." London: Greater London Council, 1977., May 1977; Pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Original Publication: 3 pages, missing
- Docklands Development Team. "Jubilee/River Line - Alignment of Custom House. Docks 200." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., June 9, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Development Team. "Draft Beckton District Plan. Docks 196." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977.", June 9, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Development Team. "Greater London (Tollgate Road, Newham) Compulsory Purchase Orger 1975: Secretary of State's Interim Decision. Docks 164." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., January 8, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Joint Committee Finance Officer. "Return of Expenditure for Seven Months to 31 October 1976: P2 Programme. Docks 161." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., December 29, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Photocopy: 1 page
- Docklands Joint Committee Finance Officer. "Financial Commitments at 31 March 1976. Docks 162." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., January 19, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Joint Committee Finance Officer. "Return of Expenditure for Year Ended 31 March 1976. Docks 142." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., October 15, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Chairman of the Officers' Steering Group of the Docklands Joint Committee. "Industrial Development in Docklands - Organisation. Docks 141." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., October 19, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Development Team. "Progress Report of the Docklands Joint Committee. Docks 116." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., February 10, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Development Team. "Progress Report of the Docklands Joint Committee. Docks 156." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., November 18, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Secretary of the Docklands Forum. "Docklands Forum meeting 1 December 1976. Docks 159." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., December 1, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Development Team. "Progess Report of the Docklands Joint Committee. Docks 76." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1975., August 22, 1975; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Development Team. "Government's Inner City Proposals - Implications for Docklands. Docks 201." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1977., June 10, 1977; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Joint Committee. "Report of Chairman's Action. Item 3, Docks 134." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., Spetember 8, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Docklands Development Team. "Redevelopment of London Docks Phase I Proposals by Riverside London. Docks 123." London: Docklands Joint Committee, 1976., May 3, 1976; Document (Box 1, Folder 23)